

Software Developer

**(**+91)8981319848/ (+91)9038882163

🔀 guptaswati2121@gmail.com

in swatigupta8

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Work experience of over 3 years in database design and management, with strong hands-on experience in PL/SQL and Python, in the health care domain. Keeps the ability to understand front-end users' requirements. Possesses good analytical and excellent problem-solving skills. Always ready to face any challenges.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Applied Research Works India Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata

Software Development Engineer III (August 2019-Present)

- · Implemented end-to-end design of data architecture and workflow for launch of a major customer
- Optimized several existing routines with up to 70% improved performance
- Coordinating with CSMs to get customer requirements, also mentor junior developers

# Applied Research Works India Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata

Software Development Engineer I (July 2017- August 2019)

- Worked on over 50 measures to obtain HEDIS/ AMP certifications and updated them on Production
- Interaction with UI and QA teams to get smooth delivery of my developed features

# Variable Energy Cyclotron Centre, Dept. of Atomic Energy, Govt. of India, Kolkata Trainee (June 2016-July 2016)

• Development of Read- out Module (using C) for High Resolution Encoder- used to convert rotation of the valve of the cyclotron tube

## Primetals Technologies India Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata

Intern (June 2015-July 2015)

• Programming for Automation using Step 7 software (by SIEMENS) and Comparative Study of Rectifiers

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Recognized as MVP by present employer for developing an editable form from scratch with no bugs
- Won several awards in table-tennis tournaments held at district level, community level, intra-murals
- Part of prefectorial board in both standards IX-X and XI-XII in school

# **EDUCATION**

#### Institute of Engineering & Management, Kolkata, MAKAUT (formerly WBUT) (2013-2017)

Bachelor of Technology in ECE with DGPA 9.34

Bhavan's Gangabux Kanoria Vidyamandir, Kolkata, CBSE (2013)

Higher Secondary Education (Science) with 93.4%

#### Bhavan's Gangabux Kanoria Vidyamandir, Kolkata, CBSE (2011)

Secondary Education with CGPA 10/10 or 95%

# SKILLS

- Test Driven Development, Debugging, Critical Thinking, Quick Grasping, Cooperative, Decision Making
- Word, Excel, Power Point
- Windows, LINUX, DOS
- RDBMS, PL/SQL, Python, Shell Script, AWS, OOPS, Data Structures, Algorithms, C++, Java, MATLAB

## HOBBIES

Table Tennis, Dancing, Food Blogging

#### LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Bengali